Having felt an earnest call to ministry since college, I have been preparing for both foreign missions and domestic church ministry through internship opportunities, academic study, voracious reading, intense dialog, and a foray into electronic publishing. While my primary focus has been church health, including church planting and church strengthening, I have been gifted in personal counseling and have experience in adoption ministry. I hope to transition into ministry prior to or upon graduation. I affirm the Abstract of Principles, the Baptist Faith and Message 2000, the Chicago Statement on Biblical Inerrancy, and the Danvers Statement on Biblical Manhood and Womanhood.

# **Personal Background**

# **Spouse**

Kathryn Rose, married December 22, 2007

### Children

Vernon Ray, IV (10), Brooklyn Leigh (7), Emma Grace (3), Seth Christopher (infant)

Our three eldest came into the family in 2011.

#### Contact

1085 Thornrose Way Wake Forest, North Carolina 27587 <a href="mailto:vernon.king@outlook.com">vernon.king@outlook.com</a> | (817) 458–8174

Personal blog: <a href="http://www.pjking.net">http://www.pjking.net</a>

Family blog: http://www.adoptedbytheking.com



## **Education**

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Currently pursuing *Master of Divinity in Christian Ministry* 

Anticipated completion: Summer 2014

GPA: 4.0

Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary | Fort Worth, Texas

Coursework toward Master of Divinity in Missions

GPA: 4.0+

2009 - 2011

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

GPA: 4.0, summa cum laude

May 2007

# **Relevant Experience**

# New Song Church | Windhoek, Namibia

Missionary Intern

May 2007 - August 2007

Residential intern with an IMB missionary church and youth ministry:

- Assisted in the leadership and administration of a 150+ youth outreach program
- Helped host two American youth mission teams for two weeks each
- Provided technical support for church, youth ministries, and camp

#### Pillar on the Rock | Ecclesiological Online Magazine

Co-founder and Editor, www.pillarontherock.com

2009 - 2011

Wrote and edited articles promoting healthy local churches:

- Article reprinted in B&H book, Preach: Theology Meets Practice, by Dever and Gilbert
- Edited 100+ articles; Authored 50+ articles (<u>www.pillarontherock.com/search/label/PJ King</u>)
- Wrote major series on divorce and remarriage, race, membership, and church discipline
- Grew the writing team to include six authors

# **Church Background**

### First Baptist Church | Durham, North Carolina

Member 2013 – Present

Although a new member, I am scheduled to serve in the following ways:

- Rotating Children's Sunday School and home group teacher
- Pastoral internship through Southeastern in Spring 2014

#### Church of Christ the King (SBC) | Fort Worth, Texas

*Member* 2010 – 2012

Considered faithful to the community and participated in *ad hoc* duties:

- Deacon candidate (moved out of town soon after nomination)
- Organized greeter and security rotations
- Administered web technologies

#### Portland Avenue Baptist Church | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

*Member* 2008 – 2009

Sacrificially served while discerning future ministry goals:

- Interim Sunday School teacher for College and Career class
- Break-out teacher for youth ministry
- Assumed temporary guardianship for twin teenage girls from the youth group

Trinity Baptist Church | Norman, Oklahoma

Attended 2007 – 2008

Actively participated before planned move out of town.

First Baptist Church | Bryan, Texas

Member 2003 – 2007

Engaged in ministry during full tenure of college:

- Served as a youth leader
- Participated in college discipleship programs

First Baptist Church | Woodway, Texas

Member 1992 – 2003

Raised by my parents to be a faithful member:

- Baptized by Michael Toby, 1992
- Served on student leadership team during high school
- Counseled as a college leader for youth camps and mission trips

# **Professional History**

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Software Developer May 2013 – Present

FTS International | Fort Worth, Texas

Lead Software Developer May 2011 – January 2013

Led a team of five engineers and served as a point of contact with management

Deloitte Consulting | Dallas, Texas

Software Consultant, Homeland Security January 2011 – May 2011

FIS | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Senior Programmer Analyst October 2009 – November 2010
Programmer Analyst II September 2007 – October 2009

Hewlett-Packard | College Station, Texas

ASIC Intern May 2006 – May 2007

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Peer Teacher, Department of Computer Science September 2004 – May 2006

# References

## Nathan Finn

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Associate Professor, Historical Theology and Baptist Studies, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary (919) 280-4309

nfinn@sebts.edu

## Ryan Hutchinson

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Executive Vice President for Operations, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary
(919) 761-2200

hutchinson@sebts.edu

## Benjamin H. Arbour

Mentor and Friend (979) 574-1300 benarbour03@yahoo.com

### David Jacks

Elder, Church of Christ the King (817) 395-2180 davidjacks1967@gmail.com

## Jonathan Dent

Elder, Church of Christ the King (404) 667-7765 jdent\_gt@yahoo.com